I love museums.
أنا أحب المتاحف.
Have you guys ever been to the Natural History Museum?
هل زرتم متحف التاريخ الطبيعي من قبل؟
In New York City?
في مدينة نيويورك
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So one of the things that I do is I take my kids to the museum.
إحدى الأشياء التي أقوم بها هي أخذ أطفالي إلى المتحف.
Recently I took them to the Natural History Museum.
مؤخرا ذهبت بهم إلى متحف التاريخ الطبيعي.
I had my two sons with me, Sabian and Dabith.
كان معي طفلي سيبيان ودابيث.
And we go into the front entrance of the museum,
ذهبنا معا إلى المدخل الأمامي للمتحف،
and there's that amazing sculpture of Teddy Roosevelt out there.
حيث يوجد التمثال المدهش لتيدي روزفلت.
You guys know which one I'm talking about.
تعلمون عما أتحدث.
Teddy Roosevelt is sitting there with one hand on the horse,
هناك يجلس تيدي زوفلت بيد واحدة على الحصان
bold, strong, sleeves rolled up.
بجرأة، وقوة، ودرع معدني ملتف حول ذراعه.
I don't know if he's bare-chested, but it kind of feels like it.
لا أدري إذا كان صدره عاريا، لكن كأنه كذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And on the left-hand side of him is a Native American walking.
وفي الناحية اليسرى ليده يمشي رجل أمريكي الأصل.
And on the right-hand side of him is an African-American walking.
وفي الناحية اليمنى يمشي رجل أمريكي إفريقي.
And as we're moving up the stairs,
وبينما نحن نذهب أعلى السلالم،
getting closer to the sculpture,
شيئا فشيئا نقترب للـتمثال،
my oldest son, who's nine, says,
ابني الأكبر، ذو التاسعة من العمر يقول:
"Dad, how come he gets to ride,
"أبي، لما هو الذي يمتطي حصان
and they have to walk?"
وهم وجب عليهم المشي؟"
It stopped me in my tracks.
توقفت مندهشا.
There was so much history
هنالك أشياء كثيرة مؤرخة
that we would have to go through to try to explain that,
التي يجب علينا أن ننظر من خلالها ومحاولة شرحها
and that's something I try to do with them anyways.
هذا ما أحاول أن أفعله معهم على أي حال
It's a question that I probably would have never really asked.
إنه سؤال لم أسأله أبدا من قبل
But fundamentally what he was saying was,
لكن في الأساس ما يقوله هو:
"That doesn't look fair.
"هذا لا يبدو عادلاً
Dad, that doesn't look fair.
أبي، هذا لا يبدو عادلاََ
And why is this thing that's so not fair
ولماذا هذا الشيء غير العادل أبدا
sitting outside of such an amazing institution."
يجلس خارج هذا البناء المدهش."
And his question got me wondering,
سؤاله جعلني أتساءل
is there a way for us to amend our public sculptures,
هل هنالك طريقة لإصلاح تماثيلنا العامة،
our national monuments?
آثارنا الوطنية؟
Not erase them,
ليس محوهم
but is there a way to amend them?
لكن طريقة لإصلاحهم؟
Now, I didn't grow up going to museums.
لم اعتد على الذهاب إلى المتاحف في صغري.
That's not my history.
هذا ليس تاريخي.
My mother was 15 years old when I was born.
كانت أمي في عمر 15 عندما ولدتني،
She is amazing.
إنها مدهشة.
My father was struggling with his own things
كان أبي يكافح من أجل أموره الخاصة
for most of my life.
في معظم حياتي
If you really want to know the truth,
إذا كنتم تريدون حقا معرفة الحقيقة،
the only reason I got into art is because of a woman.
السبب الوحيد الذي أدخلني عالم الفن هـو امرأة.
There was this amazing, amazing, fantastic, beautiful, smart woman,
كانت هنالك امرأة مدهشة ورائعة وجميلة وذكية
four years older than me,
تكبرني أربع سنوات
and I wanted to go out with her.
أردتُ الخروج معها.
But she said, "You're too young
لكنها قالت: "أنت صغير جداً
and you're not thinking about your future."
كما أنك لا تفكر في مستقبلك."
So I ran on down to the junior college,
بعدها ذهبت إلى كلية المبتدئين
registered for some classes,
سجلت ببعض الحصص
ran on back,
ثم رجعت
and basically was like, "I'm thinking about my future now."
على هذا الأساس "أنا أفكر في مستقبلي الآن."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Can we go out?"
"هل يمكنني مواعدتك؟"
For the record, she's even more amazing.
لبرهة، كانت مندهشة للــغــاية
I married her.
تــزوجــتـهــا.
(Applause)
( تــــــــصـــفـيـــق)
So when I randomly ran down to the junior college
وبـالـتـالي عـنـدمـا ذهــبـت لـكـلـية المـبـتـدئـيـن بـعـشـوائية
and registered for classes,
وسـجـلـتُ في الــحــصــص
I really wasn't paying attention to what I was registering to.
لم أنـــتبه بمـــا ســــجلت.
(Laughter)
(ضـــحـــك)
So I ended up with an art history class,
انتهى بي المطاف في حصص فن التاريخ
and I didn't know a thing about art history.
لم أكن أعرف شيئاً عن التاريخ.
But something amazing happened when I went into that class.
لكـن عنـدما ذهبت لتـلك الحصة حصل شيء مدهش.
For the first time in my academic career,
ولأول مـرة في سـيـرة حــيـاتي الأكاديمية،
my visual intelligence was required of me.
كان ذكــائي الـبصري مطلوبا بالنسبة لي.
For the first time.
لأول مــرة
The professor would put up an image,
وضع البروفسور صورا
bold strokes of blues and yellows, and say, "Who's that?"
خطوط زرقاء وصفراء عريضة وقال: "مـن هـذا؟"
And I'd go, "That's Van Gogh. Clearly that is Van Gogh.
و بهمة شرعت في قول "هذا فان غوخ" واضح أن هذا فان غوخ
I got this."
عرفته."
(Laughter)
(ضـــحـــك)
I got a B in that class.
حـصـلـت عـلـى درجة (ب) في تلك الحصة.
For me, that was amazing.
بالــنــســبــة لـي، كـان ذلك مـدهــشـاً.
In high school, let's just say I wasn't a great student. OK?
فــي الــثــانــويـة، دعونا نقول لم أكُن طـالباً بــارعــاً. حسنا؟
In high school, my GPA was .65.
في مرحلتي الثانوية كـان معدلي التراكمي 0.65
(Laughter)
(ضــحــك)
Decimal point first, six five.
النقطة العشرية أولاً، ثم الستة ثم الخمسة.
So me getting a B was huge, huge,
لذا حصولي على درجة (ب) كان عظيماً
absolutely huge.
كــان عـظـيـمـاً حقّـاََ.
And because of the fact that I realized that I was able to learn things visually
بسبب هذه الحقيقة أدركت أنني يمكنني تعلم الأشياء بصريا
that I couldn't learn in other ways,
و ليس بطريقة أخرى غير ذلك
this became my strategy, this became my tactic
أصـبـحـت هذه هي استراتيجيتي ونهجي
for understanding everything else.
لفهم كل شيء.
I wanted to stay in this relationship. Things were going well.
أردتُ البقاء في هذه العلاقة كانت الأمور جيدة
I decided, let me keep taking these art history classes.
قررت بأن أكمل هذه الحصص التاريخية الفنية
One of the last art history classes, I will not forget, I will never forget.
آخر إحدى الحصص التاريخية الفنية، لن أنساها لن أنساها أبدأً.
It was one of those survey art history classes.
كانت تلك من إحدى حصص دراسة تاريخ فن الإستقصاء
Anybody ever have one of those survey art history classes,
هل من أحد أبداً عنده تلك الحصص دراسة تاريخ الفن الاستقصائي
where they try to teach you the entire history of art
عندما يحاولون تعليمك كل ما يتضمنه تاريخ الفن
in a single semester?
في فـصـل دراسي واحد؟
I'm talking about cave paintings and Jackson Pollock
أنا أتحدث عن لوحات الكهف وجاكسون بولوك
just crunched together all in the same --
طحنوا ببعضهم البعض والكل يتشابه
It doesn't really work, but they try anyway.
هذا لا ينجح لكنهم حاولوا على أي حال.
Well, at the beginning of the semester,
طبعاً، في بداية الفصل الدراسي
I looked at the book,
اطلعت على الكتاب لبرهه
and in this 400-page book was about a 14-page section
وفي هذا الكتاب ذو الأربعمائة صفحة كان هناك قسم من أربع عشرة صفحة
that was on black people in painting.
كان مليئًا برسومات الناس السود.
Now, this was a crammed in section
وهذا ما كان يملأ القسم
that had representations of black people in painting
كان ذاك تمثيلاً للسود بالرسم
and black people who painted.
والناس السود الذين رسموا.
It was poorly curated, let's just put it that way.
كانت منسقة بتلك الطريقة السيئة، دعونا نفكر فيها بهذه الطريقة.
(Laughter)
(ضــحـــك)
Nonetheless I was really excited about it,
بالرغم من ذلك، كنت حـقـاً متحمساََ إزائها،
because in all the other classes that I had,
بسبب كل الحصص الأخرى التي ارتدتها،
we didn't even have that conversation.
لم نخض في الحديث عن ذلك.
We didn't talk about it at all.
لم نخض في الحديث مطلقا.
So imagine my surprise
لذا تخيلوا المفاجئة
when I get to class
عندما كنت في الصف
and on the day that we're supposed to go over that particular chapter,
وفي ذلك اليوم الذي من المفترض أن ندرس ذاك الفصل،
my professor announces,
يعلن البروفسور،
"We're going to skip this chapter today
"سوف نتخطى اليوم هذا الفصل
because we do not have time to go through it."
ذلك أننا ليس لدينا الزمن الكافي لنتدارسه."
"Whoa, I'm sorry, hold on, professor, professor.
"آه آه أنا آسف جداً، تـمـهـلي، يــا أستاذة، أستاذة.
I'm sorry. This is a really important chapter to me.
أنا آسف، هذا الفصل مهم حقاً بالنسبة لي
Are we going to go over it at any point?"
هل بوسعنا أن نتدارسه بأي نقطة مــا؟"
"Titus, we don't have time for this."
" تيتيوس، ليس لدينا وقت لهذا"
"I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
"أنا آسف، أنا آسف أنا آسف، أنا آسف
please, I really need to understand.
رجـــاء، أريد حقا أن أفهم لماذا
Clearly the author thinks that this is significant.
من الواضح أن المؤلف يظن أن هذا ذو أهمية
Why are we skipping over this?"
لما نتخطى هذا؟"
"Titus, I do not have time for this."
"تيتيوس، ليس لدي وقت لهذا."
"OK, last question, I'm really sorry here.
"أجل، سؤالٌ أخير، أنا حقا آسف هنا.
When can we talk, because we need to talk."
متى يمكننا التحدث عن ذلك لأننا نحتاج للتحدث."
(Laughter)
(ضحـك)
I went to her office hours.
ذهبت في ساعات وجودها بمكتبها.
I ended up getting kicked out of her office.
وجدت نفسي مطرودا خارج مكتبها
I went to the dean.
ذهبت إلى العميد
The dean finally told me, "I can't force her to teach anything."
فأخبرني العميد في النهاية: "لا يمكنني إجبارها على تدريس كل شيء."
And I knew in that moment if I wanted to understand this history,
في تلك اللحظة عرفت أنني إذا أردتُ فهم هذا التاريخ،
if I wanted to understand the roles of those folks who had to walk,
إذا أردتُ فهم أدوار أولئك القوم اللذين كان عليهم المشي،
I was probably going to have to figure that out myself.
كان من الأرجح علي معرفة ذلك بنفسي.
So ...
لهذا...
above you right here on the slide
فوق، مباشرةً هنا عند شرائح العرض
is a painting by Frans Hals.
إنها رسم لوحة فرانس هالس
This is one of the kinds of images
هذه، هذا النوع من الصور
that was in that chapter.
كانت في ذاك الفصل من الكتاب
I taught myself how to paint
علمت نفسي كيف أرسم
by going to museums and looking at images like this.
بذهابي للمتحف ونظري للصور مثل هذه.
I want to show you something.
أريد أن أريكم شيئًا.
I made this.
صنعت هذا.
I --
أنا...
(Applause)
(تــصـــفـــيــق)
I made some alterations.
صنعت بعض التبديلات.
You'll see there are some slight differences in the painting.
سوف ترون بعض الاختلافات الطفيفة في هذه اللوحة.
All this art history that I had been absorbing
كل تاريخ الفن هذا، الذي كنت استوعبه
helped me to realize that painting is a language.
ساعدني بأن أدرك أن الرسم عبارة عن لغة.
There is a reason
هنالك سبب
why he is the highest in the composition here.
لماذا هو الأعلى في التكوين هنا.
why the painter is showing us this gold necklace here.
لماذا يرينا الرسام هذا العقد الذهبي هنا
He's trying to tell us something about the economic status
يحاول أن يرينا شيئا ما عن الوضع الإقتصادي
of these people in these paintings.
لهؤلاء الناس في تلك اللوحات.
Painting is a visual language
الرسم هو لغة مرئية
where everything in the painting
حيث كل شيء في الرسم
is meaningful, is important.
له مغزى وأهميّة
It's coded.
وله شفرة.
But sometimes, because of the compositional structure,
لكن في بعض الأوقات، بسبب التركيب التكويني
because of compositional hierarchy,
بسبب التكوين الهرمي،
it's hard to see other things.
من الصعب رؤية أشياء أخرى.
This silk is supposed to tell us also that they have quite a bit of money.
هذه المهارة من المفترض أيضا أن تخبرنا أن لديهم بعض النقود.
There's more written
هناك الكثير قد كُتب
about dogs in art history
عن الكلاب في تاريخ الفن
than there are about this other character here.
ثم إن هنالك عن هذه الشخصية الأخرى هنا.
Historically speaking, in research on these kinds of paintings,
تاريخياً أتحدث في البحث عن هذا النوع من الرسومات،
I can find out more about the lace
بمقدرتي إيجاد الكثير عن العقد
that the woman is wearing in this painting --
الذي ترتديه تلك المرأة في هذه اللوحة
the manufacturer of the lace -- than I can about this character here,
مصنّع هذا العقد ثم ما أستطيع أن أفعل حول هذه الشخصية هنا،
about his dreams, about his hopes,
ماذا عن أحلامه، ماذا عن آماله
about what he wanted out of life.
ماذا عن ما يريده من الحياة.
I want to show you something.
أريد أن أريكم شيئاً.
I don't want you to think
لا أريدكم أن تظنوا
that this is about eradication.
أن هذا عن استئصال الهوية.
It's not.
ليس هذا
The oil that you saw me just put inside of this paint
اللون الزيتي الذي ترونه أنا فقط وضعته داخل الرسم
is linseed oil.
هو زيت بذر الكتان.
It becomes transparent over time,
يمكنه أن يصبح شفافاََ مع مرور الزمن،
so eventually what's going to happen
لذا ماذا يمكن أن يحدث في آخر المطاف
is these faces
هل تلك الوجوه
will emerge a little bit.
سوف تبدأ بالظهور قليلا
What I'm trying to do,
ما أحاول فعله،
what I'm trying to show you,
ما أحاول أن أريكم إياه،
is how to shift your gaze just slightly,
هو كيف تحولون نظركم قليلا فقط،
just momentarily,
فقط للحظة،
to ask yourself the question,
لتسألوا أنفسكم سؤالًا،
why do some have to walk?
لماذا يتوجب على البعض المشي؟
What is the impact of these kinds of sculptures at museums?
ما تأثير هذا النوع من التماثيل في المتحف؟
What is the impact of these kinds of paintings
ما تأثير هذا النوع من الرسوم
on some of our most vulnerable in society,
على بعض من أكثر الفئات ضعفا في المجتمع،
seeing these kinds of depictions of themselves all the time?
بالنظر إلى هذه الأنواع من التصوير عن نفسهم في كل حين؟
I'm not saying erase it.
أنا لا أقول امسحها.
We can't erase this history.
لا يمكننا حذف التاريخ.
It's real. We have to know it.
إنه حقيقي، يجب علينا معرفة ذلك.
I think of it in the same way
أنا افكر فيه بنفس الطريقة
we think of --
التي نفكر بها
Let me step back a second.
دعوني أرجع إلى الوراء لثانية.
You remember old-school cameras,
هل تذكرون كاميرات التصوير القديمة
where when you took a picture, you actually had to focus. Right?
عندما تلتقط صورة، في الحقيقة يجب أن تركز في التصوير، أليس كذلك؟
You'd put the camera up,
سوف تضع الكاميرا،
and if I wanted you in focus,
وإذا أردت أن أجعلكم تركزون،
I would move the lens a little to the left
سوف أحرك العدسات إلى اليسار قليلا
and you would come forward.
وأنتم سوف تتقدمون للأمام.
I could move the lens a little to the right,
يمكنني تحريك العدسات إلى اليمين قليلاً،
and you would go back and the folks in the background would come out.
وأنتم قد تتقدموا إلى الوراء وهؤلاء الذين بالخلفية سوف يتقدموا للأمام.
I'm just trying to do that here.
أنا فقط أحاول عمل ذلك هنا.
I'm trying to give you that opportunity.
أنا أحاول أن أعطيكم، هذه الفرصة.
I'm trying to answer that question
أنا أحاول الإجابة عن هذا السؤال
that my son had.
الذي سأله ابني.
I want to make paintings,
أريد أن أصنع لوحات،
I want to make sculptures
أُريد أن أصنع تماثيل،
that are honest,
بوسعها أن تكون صادقة،
that wrestle with the struggles of our past
والتي قد تتصارع مع عقبات الماضي
but speak to the diversity and the advances of our present.
لكي تتحدث إلى التنوع والتقدم لحاضرنا.
And we can't do that by taking an eraser and getting rid of stuff.
نحن لا يمكننا فعل ذلك بأخذ ممحاة والتقدم للنيل من هذه الأشياء.
That's just not going to work.
هذا لن ينجح.
I think that we should do it in the same way
أظن أن علينا فعلها بنفس الطريقة
the American Constitution works.
الدستور الأمريكي قد ينجح.
When we have a situation
عندما يكون هنالك وضع
where we want to change a law in the American Constitution,
عندما نريد تغيير قانون ما بالدستور الأمريكي
we don't erase the other one.
نحن لا نمحي الذي قبله
Alongside that is an amendment,
جنبا إلى ذلك إنه الـــتــعــديــل،
something that says,
شيء ما قد يقول،
"This is where we were, but this is where we are right now."
هذا ما كنّا عليه، لكن هذا ما نحن عليه الآن
I figure if we can do that,
عرفت أنه إذا أمكننا فعل ذلك،
then that will help us understand a little bit
يمكن أن يساعدنا هذا على الفهم قليلا
about where we're going.
عن ما سيمضي بنا.
Thank you.
شُـكـراً لـكـم.